Do you surrender?
هل تستسلم؟
(Young Guo Jing) No! I won't!
(الشباب غو جينغ) لا! لن أسلم!
I won't surrender! Never!
لن أستسلم أبدا!
Pull him up! Kowtow to me!
اسحبوه! اركضوا لي!
(Young Tolui) Guo Jing, run! Don't mind me!
(يونغ توولي) قاو جينغ، اركض! لا تأبه بي!
Stay away, all of you!
ابتعدوا جميعًا!
Guo Jing,
قوه جينغ
(Young Dushi) I'm dealing with Tolui. Why do you care?
(الدوشي الشاب) أنا أتعامل مع التولي لماذا تهتم؟
If you dare hurt him,
إذا كنت تجرؤ على إيذائه
I'll kill you!
سأقتلك!
(Ke Zhen'e, nicknamed Flying Bat, from Seven Freaks of Jiangnan)
(كي جين هي اللقب "فاكلينغ بات" من سبع مقاطعات من جيانغنان)
This dagger
هذا الخنجر
is yours?
هو لك؟
Your surname is Yang?
لقبك هو يانغ؟
No, it's Guo.
لا، إنه غو
Kid, what's your mother's name?
أيها الأطفال، ما اسم أمك؟
My mother's Li Ping.
لي بينغ لأمي
And your father?
وأبوك؟
My father's Guo Xiaotian.
أبي قوه شياوتيان
Kid, we've been searching for you for six years.
أيها الأطفال، لقد كنا نبحث عنك منذ ست سنوات
(Quan Jinfa, nicknamed Hidden Hero) We want to find you,
(وان جينفا، البطل المخفي) نريد العثور عليك
(Nan Xiren, nicknamed Southern Hill Woodcutter)
(نان شيرين، اللقب كالزبير لخشب التيل الجنوبي)
(Han Xiaoying, nicknamed Yue Maiden Sword) teach you martial arts
(هان شياو ينغ، سيف يويه مايدن) يعلمك فنون الدفاع عن النفس
(Zhang Asheng, nicknamed Laughing Buddha) and help you seek revenge.
(تشانغ آشنغ، البنت بوذا) ومساعدتك في البحث عن الانتقام
(Zhu Cong, nicknamed Marvellous-Handed Scholar) What do you think?
(زهو كونغ، اللقب مارفيلوس - باحث متقاعد) ما رأيك؟
(Han Baoju, nicknamed Horse Deity, from Seven Freaks of Jiangnan)
(هان باوجو، إله الحصان، من سبع مقاطعات من جيانغنان)
I agree. I want to become powerful
أوافقك الرأي، أريد أن أصبح قويا
to avenge my father.
للانتقام من والدي
Seven masters,
سبعة سياد
please accept my kowtou.
يرجى قبول الركوع الخاص بي
(From that day on,)
(من ذلك اليوم فصاعدا)
(I became a disciple of Seven Heroes of Jiangnan.)
(أصبحت تلميذا من سبعة أبطال من جيانغنان)
(That year,)
(ذلك العام،)
(the martial world was rife with killings.)
(كان عالم القتال رائعا بالقتل)
(The evil Twin Killers in the Dark Wind)
(الطاعون الأشرار في الرياح البحرية)
(Mei Chaofeng) (also came to the desert.)
(مي تشاوفنغ) (جاء أيضا إلى الصحراء)
(Chen Xuanfeng) (They held me hostage)
(تشن شوانفنغ) (احتجزوا أنا كرهائن)
(for killing my masters.)
(لقتل سيادي)
(Maybe I was young and fearless,)
(ربما كنت صغيرا ولا خائفا)
(in that big battle,)
(في تلك المعركة الكبيرة،)
(I accidentally stabbed)
(طعنت عن طريق الخطأ)
(Copper Corpse Chen Xuanfeng's vulnerable area.)
(منطقة تشن شيوانفنغ الضعيفة)
(And he died.)
(وهو مات)
(Iron Corpse Mei Chaofeng turned blind and escaped.)
(جعل مي تشاوفنغ أعمى وهرب)
(Asheng's tomb. Wife Hanxiaoying) (But my fifth master Zhang Asheng)
(قبر أشنغ والزوجة هاناكياينغ) (لكن سيدنا الخامس تشانغ أشنغ)
(died in the chaotic battlefield.)
(مات في ساحة المعركة الفوضوية)
Jing, rise up.
جينغ، استعد
Fifth Master died saving me,
مات السيد الخامس لإنقاذي
I feel bad.
أشعر بالأسف
We live and die in the martial world.
نحن نعيش ونموت في عالم القتال
This is our fate.
هذا هو قدرنا
Your Fifth Master fought for justice.
قاتل معلمك الخامس من أجل العدالة
He died a worthy death.
مات موتا يستحق الموت
You must diligently practice martial arts,
يجب أن تمارس بنشاط فنون الدفاع عن النفس
and master our martial arts.
وإتقان فنون الدفاع عن النفس لدينا
Then your master can rest his soul.
إذن يمكن أن يرتاح معلمك روحه
Disciple will not disappoint
تلميذة لن أخيب أمل
masters' expectations!
توقعات السيدات!
(From then on,)
(من ذلك الحين فصاعدا)
(I learned martial arts from my six masters.)
(تعلمت فنون الدفاع عن النفس من سادة الستة)
(such as fist position, swordsmanship, assassination weapons, and inner energy.)
(مثل موقف القبضة، والرداء، وأسلحة الاغتيال، والطاقة الداخلية)
(They taught me everything.)
(علموا لي كل شيء)
(But...)
(لكن)
Jing is not talented in martial arts.
جينغ ليس موهوبا في فنون الدفاع عن النفس
We taught him ten moves.
علمناه عشر تحركات
He can learn at most one.
يمكنه أن يتعلم واحدة على الأكثر
That boy Jing
ذلك الصبي جينغ
is really...
هو حقا...
Big brother,
أخ كبير
maybe we should send this boy
ربما يجب أن نرسل هذا الصبي
back to that cow-nosed bun Taoist.
عودي إلى ذلك الكعكة الطاوية التي تعمل بالفحم
We just admit defeat
نسلم بالهزيمة فحسب
in that bet, okay?
في ذلك أراهن، حسنا؟
If that's the case,
إذا كان هذا هو الحال
won't my Fifth Brother's death be in vain?
ألن تذهب وفاة أخي الخامس بلا جدوى؟
We made a vow back then.
لقد صنعنا إذن تعهدًا
Now we're giving up halfway.
نحن الآن نتخلى عن منتصف الطريق
How can we face the Central Plains again?
كيف يمكننا مواجهة السهل المركزي مجددًا؟
Don't lose heart.
لا تفكري في القلب
Though Jing is not gifted,
على الرغم من أن جينغ ليس موهوب
he is obedient and hardworking.
هو مطيع ويعمل بجد
- Heaven rewards diligence. - Punch hard.
- عناية مكافآت ثقيلة - ترافق بقوة
- He has the potential. - Stand still.
- لديه الإمكانية - قف مع ذلك
- Exactly. - Good. Again.
- بالضبط - جيد، مجددًا
We Seven Freaks of Jiangnan
نحن سبع مقاطعات من جيانغنان
always keep our promises.
نفي بوعودنا دائما
We never back down!
لا نتراجع أبدا!
(Guo Jing)
(غو جينغ)
=The Legend of Heroes=
= رائحة الأبطال =
=Hot Blooded=
= مدونة الساخنة =
=Episode 1=
= الحلقة 1 =
Got beaten again.
ضُرب مرة أخرى
How did practice?
كيف تدرب؟
Your palm strength is so weak.
قوتك في النخيل ضعيفة جدًا
Second Brother, you hit too hard.
يا أخي، لقد ضربت بشدة
This is a letter from the Zhongnan Mountain.
هذه رسالة من جبل تشونغنان
What's it say?
ما قولها؟
It says Qiu Chuji
تقول تشيو تشوجي
found a Yang Tiexin's descendant
وجدت سليل يانغ تيهشين
and taken him as a disciple.
وأخذه كتلميذ
He mentioned the upcoming
أشار إلى الاجتماع المقبل
Jiaxing Martial Arts Duel two years later.
بعد سنتين من ذلك
Seems he's very confident.
يبدو أنه واثق جدا
Jing's martial arts
فنون الدفاع عن النفس في جينغ
hasn't improved much in the past couple of decades.
لم تتحسن كثيرا في العقدين الماضيين
The duel is approaching,
المبارزة تقترب
Jing may not be able to win.
قد لا يكون جينغ قادرا على الفوز
What if he gets injured?
ماذا لو أصيب؟
How can we tell his mother?
كيف يمكننا أن نخبر والدته؟
(My masters said,)
(قال سيادي،)
(when I turn 18,)
(عندما أصبح 18 سنة،)
(I must go to Jiangnan to duel with someone.)
(يجب أن أذهب إلى جيانغنان لتناول الطعام مع أحدهم)
(He is my sworn brother)
(إنه أخي المحلف)
(named Yang Kang.)
(اسمه "يانغ كانغ")
It won't work
لن ينجح
even if you practice for a hundred years!
حتى لو تدربت لمدة مائة عام!
Excuse me?
معذرةً؟
Watch this.
انتبه لهذا
May I ask who you are?
هل يمكنني أن أسأل من أنت؟
Your masters
سيادتك
are all top martial artists.
جميعهم من أكبر فنانين قتاليين
These past ten years,
في هذه السنوات العشر الماضية
they've surely trained you meticulously
لقد دربتك بالتأكيد بدقة
without holding back.
دون كبح جماحها
But your progress remains minimal.
ولكن تقدمك لا يزال منخفضا
Do you know
هل تعرف
the reason?
السبب؟
Because I'm stupid.
لأنني غبية
Masters teach me everything,
سيدي يعلمني كل شيء
but I can't learn.
لكنني لا أستطيع أن أتعلم
I doubt that.
أشك في ذلك
But
لكن
they teach without mastering the method,
إنهم يتعلمون دون إتقان الطريقة
and you learn without grasping the essence.
وتعلمت دون إدراك الجوهر
Your seven masters
السيدات السبع
made a private agreement with my junior
أبرم اتفاقا خاصا مع طفلتي الصغيرة
Qiu Chuji.
تشوجي
If I teach you privately,
إذا علمتك في مكان خاص
it would be unfair.
سيكون من غير العدل
But
لكننا
we are lucky to meet.
نحن محظوظون بأن نلتقي
I'll teach you something
سأعلمك شيئا
about breathing, walking,
عن التنفس والمشي
and sleeping.
والنوم
I have four sayings.
لديّ أربعة مقانق
You must remember them.
يجب أن تتذكرها
"Clear heart, emotions departed,
"قلب واضح، انتعشت المشاعر
in empty body Qi can spread.
في الجسد الفارغ يمكن أن تنتشر تشي
A dead mind, yet the spirit lives,
عقلا ميتا، لكن الروح تعيش
for Yin thrives but the Yang is shed."
لأن يين يزدهر ولكن يانغ يذرف "
Clear heart, emotions departed,
قلب واضح، غادرت المشاعر
in empty body Qi can spread.
في الجسد الفارغ يمكن أن تنتشر تشي
A dead mind, yet the spirit lives,
عقلا ميتا، لكن الروح تعيش
for Yin thrives but the Yang is shed."
لأن يين يزدهر ولكن يانغ يذرف "
Seems Jing gets it.
يبدو أن جينغ يحصل عليه
He is progressing so rapidly.
إنه يتقدم بسرعة كبيرة
Maybe we can win the bet.
ربما يمكننا الفوز بالدهان
Something is wrong.
هناك خطب ما
Have you noticed that?
هل لاحظت ذلك؟
Hard to say.
يصعب القول
Go test him.
اذهب للاختبار منه
Bold apprentice!
تلميذة جريئة!
I accidentally injured Second Master.
أصيب السيد الثاني بجروح عن طريق الخطأ
Please punish me.
أرجوك عاقبني
I'm annoyed with you
أنا منزعج منك
not because you hurt
ليس لأنك تأذيت
your Second Master,
أن معلمك الثاني
but because your internal martial arts.
ولكن لأن فنون الدفاع عن النفس الداخلية الخاصة بك
Who taught you this?
من علمك هذا؟
Internal martial arts?
فنون الدفاع عن النفس الداخلية؟
Is it the heat
هل هي الحرارة
swirling in my chest?
تتوسل في صدري؟
Yes, that's it.
نعم، هذا هو الأمر
Jing,
جينغ
who taught you this?
من علمك هذا؟
Six masters.
ستة سادة
These years, a senior has been instructing me
هذه السنوات، كان أحد كبار السن يقوم بالتعليمات لي
on sleeping
في النوم
and breathing.
والتنفس
But
لكن
he hasn't taught me
لم يعلمني
any moves.
أي تحركات
He also said,
قال أيضا
he might be
قد يكون أكثر مهارة
more skilled than my masters
أكثر مهارة من سيادي
and didn't allow me to call him master.
ولم أسمح لي أن أتصل به سيدي
Anything else about him?
أي شيء آخر عنه؟
He made me swear
جعلني أقسم
not to describe his appearance
ألا يصف مظهره
or movements to anyone.
أو التنقلات إلى أي شخص
Since I promised him,
بما أنني وعدته
I can't break my word.
لا يمكنني كسر كلماتي
Jing is right.
جينغ على حق
In the martial world,
في عالم القتال
we value loyalty and integrity.
نحن نقدر الولاء والنزاهة
You can go now.
يمكنك الذهاب الآن
Big brother?
أخي كبير؟
Follow him.
اتبعوه
- Go. - Okay.
- اذهب - حسنًا
I didn't expect Jing's inner energy skillls
لم أكن أتوقع مهارات جينغ الداخلية في مجال الطاقة
to be so impressive.
أن تكون مذهلة جدًا
That mysterious person must be up there.
يجب أن يكون ذلك الشخص الغامض هناك
Big brother, what should we do?
أخي الكبير، ماذا يجب أن نفعل؟
Let's follow him and see.
لنتابعه ونر
Everyone, play things by ear.
ليلعب الجميع أشياء عن طريق الأذن
Big brother.
أخ كبير
It's an old acquaintance.
إنه أحد المعارف القديمة
The person on the mountain
الشخص الذي على الجبل
is Mei Chaofeng!
هو مي تشاوفنغ!
What?
ماذا؟
Jing is learning
جينغ يتعلم
martial arts from that demoness?
فنون الدفاع عن النفس من تلك الشياطين؟
I can't believe
لا أستطيع أن أصدق
our years of effort
جهودنا على مدى سنوات
have nurtured a threat.
غذت تهديدا
Jing is loyal and honest.
جينغ مخلص وصادق
He is not an evil person.
إنه ليس شخصا شريرا
I only knew his face, not his heart.
كنت أعرف وجهه فقط، وليس قلبه
How can an honest person
كيف يمكن لشخص صادق
stay with such a scoundrel?
يبقى مع مثل هذه الأثقال؟
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل
Jing killed Copper Corpse Chen Xuanfeng.
قتل جينغ الأقباط كوربس تشن شوانفنغ
He's that witch's husband.
إنه زوج تلك الساحرة
That's the viciousness of Mei Chaofeng.
هذه هي شبح مي تشاوفنغ
She must have exploited Jing's passion
لا بد أنها استغلت شغف جينغ
for martial arts
من أجل فنون الدفاع عن النفس
to use him against us.
لاستخدامه ضدنا
I'm afraid if we fall into a trap,
أخشى إذا وقعنا في فخ
Jing might not escape either.
قد لا يفر جينغ أيضا
We'll be mocked forever
سنكون مخطئين إلى الأبد
if the martial world know that
إذا كان عالم القتال يعرف
we've raised an ungrateful person
لقد ربينا شخصا غير ممتن
for over a decade.
لأكثر من عقد
What are you saying?
ماذا تقول؟
Tonight,
الليلة
we'll rectify our conduct
سنصحح سلوكنا
and eradicate the evil completely!
والقضاء على الشر تماما!
Taoist, what's wrong?
تاي، ما هو الخطأ؟
Iron Corpse Mei Chaofeng.
كوربس الحديدي مي تشاوفنغ
Mei Chaofeng?
مي تشاوفنغ؟
Calm down.
اهدأ
Over the past ten years,
على مدى السنوات العشر الماضية
this demoness perfected her
هذا الشيطان يكملها
Nine Yin Skeleton Claw.
تسعة ين سكيلتون
We might not be her match.
قد لا نكون ندا لها
Let's wait for the right moment
لننتظر اللحظة المناسبة
to strike.
للإضراب
Masters.
سادة
Demoness,
شياطين
we've searched for you for ten years.
بحثنا عنك لمدة عشر سنوات
It's your time to die!
حان وقت الموت!
I've been looking for you too.
كنت أبحث عنك أيضًا
Tonight, you came to me.
الليلة، جئت إليّ
Let's settle the score.
فلنحسم النتيجة
Pay for my Fifth Brother's life!
دفعي قيمة حياة أخي الخامس!
Eradicate the evil completely!
القضاء على الشر تماما!
Jing!
جينغ!
Master!
معلمي!
I'm not your master.
أنا لست سيدك
Second Master,
معلمي الثاني
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
That demoness taught you martial arts
علّمك شياطين فنون الدفاع عن النفس
to turn you against us,
لتحويلك ضدنا
right?
صحيح
Traitor!
خائن!
I'll cripple you.
سأشلّك
Why are you standing still?
لماذا تقف ساكنًا؟
I never harm my masters.
أنا لا أضر بأسيادي أبدا
Stop with the sweet talk.
توقف بالتحدث حلو
If you can't do it,
إذا كنت لا تستطيعين القيام بذلك
I will.
سأفعل
Wait!
انتظر!
Please hold on.
انتظر رجاءً
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I am Ma Yu.
أنا ما يو
(Ma Yu, one of Seven Immortals of Quanzhen) I've long admired Seven Heroes of Jiangnan.
(ما يو، واحد من سبعة خيال من كوانجين) لطالما أُعجبت بسبعة أبطال من جيانغنان
I have no intention of interfering
لا أنوي التدخل
in your master-apprentice matters.
في أمور المتعلم الخاص بك
But I'm lucky to get acquainted with Guo Jing.
لكنني محظوظ لأتعرف على قوه جينغ
There might be some misunderstanding.
قد يكون هناك بعض سوء الفهم
Did you teach Jing
هل قمت بتعليم جينغ
internal martial arts?
فنون الدفاع عن النفس الداخلية؟
Exctly.
معذرة
I taught him without
علمته دون
Seven Heroes' permission.
دون إذن سبعة أبطال
I apologize.
أنا أعتذر
Come help!
تعالوا للمساعدة!
Master!
معلمي!
So you are a Taoist from Zhongnan Mountain.
لذلك أنت طاوي من جبل تشونغ نان
Shame on your reputable sect.
عار على طائفتك حسنة السمعة
You're just picking on the minority.
أنت تخيف فقط على الأقلية
Leaving a demoness like you
ترك شياطين مثلك
will only harm the martial world.
لن يؤدي إلا إلى إيذاء عالم القتال
Everyone wants you dead!
الجميع يريدك ميتا!
The road ahead is long.
الطريق إلى الأمام طويل
I'll fight you to the death!
سأقتلك حتى الموت!
Stop.
توقف
Jing,
جينغ
you will go to the duel alone
سوف تذهب إلى الدويل وحده
this time.
هذه المرة
Masters, won't you
سيدي، ألن تأتي معي
come with me?
تعال معي؟
Mei Chaofeng just escaped.
مي تشاوفنغ هرب للتو
Recently,
في الآونة الأخيرة
she has been appearing in the desert.
بدأت تظهر في الصحراء
We want to find her
نريد أن نجدها
while she's still injured
بينما لا تزال مصابة
and eradicate the evil completely!
للقضاء على الشر تماما!
Masters, please be careful.
أيها السادة، أرجوكم كونوا حذرين
I'll try my best and won't make you
سأبذل قصارى جهدي وعدم جعلتك
lose faces.
فقدت وجهي
You'll travel alone.
ستسافر وحدك
No master
لا معلمي
can teach you this experience.
يمكن أن يعلمك هذه التجربة
Remember my words:
أتذكر كلماتي
if you can't win, just run.
إن كنت لا تستطيعين الفوز، اركض فحسب
Yes.
نعم
Jing,
جينغ
don't forget.
لا تنس
By noon on March 24th,
بحلول ظهر يوم 24 مارس
you must make it to Zuixian Restaurant
يجب أن تجعلي الأمر إلى مطعم زويشيان
in Jiaxing Prefecture.
في مقاطعة جياكزينغ
No matter what,
بغض النظر عن أي شيء
don't miss it.
لا تفوته
Yes, Master.
نعم معلمي
It's noon on March 24th,
إنه منتصف النهار في 24 مارس
at Zuixian Restaurant in Jiaxing.
في مطعم Zuixian في جياكمة
We'll come find you after we're done
سنجدك بعد أن ننتهي
dealing with the demoness.
التعامل مع الشياطين
Yes, Master.
نعم معلمي
(Changqing Restaurant) Stop! Stop!
(مطعم تشانغتشينغ) توقفي!
Don't run!
لا تركض!
Stop!
توقف!
- Stop! - Don't run!
- توقف! - لا تركض!
Stop!
توقف!
(Huang Rong)
(هوانغ رونغ)
Buns!
الكعك!
Fresh buns!
الكعك الجديد!
Get your pendant.
خذ قلادتك
Have a look!
ألق نظرة!
Great! Great!
رائع!
Who are this stinky beggar?
من هم هذا الشحاذة؟
Dare to steal from us?
هل يجرؤ على السرقة منا؟
You want them?
هل تريدهم؟
Here you go.
ها أنت ذا
You ruined our steamed buns!
أفسدت الكعك على البخار!
How can we sell them?
كيف يمكننا بيعها؟
Hit him!
اضربيه!
Don't be rude.
لا تكن فظا
What? You want to fight?
ماذا؟ هل تريد القتال؟
No.
لا
I'll pay for the buns.
سأدفع ثمن الكعك
Is it enough?
هل يكفي؟
Alright.
حسنا
Lucky for you.
محظوظا لك
Let's go.
لنذهب
Little brother,
أخي صغير
I can
أستطيع
treat you to a good meal.
أن أقدم لك وجبة جيدة
Great.
رائع
I'm bored alone.
أشعر بالملل وحدي
Good to have a company.
من الجيد أن يكون لديك شركة
Come on in.
تفضلي بالدخول
- This way, please. - Little brother,
- بهذا الطريق، من فضلك - من فضلك - أخي الصغير
are you from Jiangnan? [*Jiangnan: regions south of the Yangtze River]
هل أنت من جيانغنان؟ [* جيانغنان: المناطق الواقعة جنوب نهر يانغتسي]
Why?
لماذا؟
My mother is from Lin'an, Zhejiang.
أمي من لين، زيجيانغ
My masters
سيادي
are from Zuojin, Jiaxing.
هم من زوجين، جياكمة
That's why your accent
لهذا السبب لهجتك
feels so...
أشعر بالكثير...
- This way. - Feels what?
- هذا الطريق - - أشعر بماذا؟
I can't say it.
لا يمكنني قول ذلك
Is it familiar?
هل هو مألوف؟
Exactly.
بالضبط
Waiter, we'll order.
نادل، سنطلب
Yes, we'll order.
نعم سنطلب
What can you order?
ماذا يمكنك أن تطلب؟
Yeah, I will order.
نعم سأطلب
What a snob.
يا لها من شبح
Do you think I can't
هل تعتقد أنني لا أستطيع
afford your food?
تحمل طعامك؟
Alright,
حسنًا
you can.
يمكنك
But weren't you the one
لكنك لم تكن الشخص
stealing buns?
سرقة الكعك؟
Yes, he's definitely a snob.
نعم، إنه شبح بالتأكيد
Big brother,
أخ كبير
You said you would treat me a meal.
قلت إنك ستتناول لي وجبة
- Can I order anything? - Little brother,
- هل يمكنني أن أطلب أي شيء؟ - أخي الصغير
you can order anything.
يمكنك أن تطلب أي شيء
What good food can you order?
ما هو الطعام اللذيذ الذي يمكنك طلبه؟
I'm afraid
أنا أخشى أنه
your best dishes
أفضل الأطباق الخاصة بك
might not suit my taste.
قد لا تناسب مذاقي
As long as you can name it,
طالما يمكنك تسميته
we can make it.
يمكننا الوصول إليه
But what if there's no one to pay
ولكن ماذا لو لم يكن هناك أحد يدفع
after the meal?
بعد الوجبة؟
Sir, what do you want?
سيدي، ماذا تريد؟
Half a jin of beef, [*jin: a weight unit]
نصف جين من لحم البقر، [* جين: وحدة وزن]
and one jin of lamb liver.
وجين من كبد الحلم
Little brother, want some wine?
أخي الصغير، هل يريد بعض النبيذ؟
Beef, lamb liver, are they good?
لحم البقر، كبد الحبار، هل هو لذيذ؟
First time in the Central Plains,
أول مرة في السهول الوسطى
I don't know
أنا لا أعرف
the local customs.
العادات المحلية
You can order some local dishes.
يمكنك طلب بعض الأطباق المحلية
So I can taste something new.
لذلك يمكنني تذوق شيء جديد
Great.
عظيم
Let's start with fruits and nuts.
دعنا نبدأ بالفواكه والجوز
Okay.
حسنًا
Give us four dried, four fresh,
أعطنا أربعة مجففة وأربعة جديدة
two sour-salted and four preserved in honey.
اثنان مملحان المصدر وأربعة محافظ عليها بالعسل
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
In this small place,
في هذا المكان الصغير
I doubt you can offer really good food.
أشك في أنك تستطيع تقديم طعام لذيذ حقا
Four dried
أربعة مجففة
are lychees, longans,
هم ليتشي ولونغيون
steamed dates, and ginkgo nuts.
والتواريخ على البخار وجوز جينيكغو
And give us whatever's in season.
وأعطنا كل شيء في موسم الأمطار
We also want sliced,
نريد أيضا أن تكون بالقطع
perfumed sour cherries
الكرز المعطر
and sour plums with ginger.
والزنجبيل الفاخر
Quite specific.
محدد للغاية
These are just the basics.
هذه هي الأساسيات فقط
I don't want to trouble you.
لا أريد أن أزعجك
Since you don't have fresh fish or shrimp here,
بما أنه ليس لديك السمك الطازج أو الروبيان هنا
give us eight main dishes
أعطنا ثمانية أطباق رئيسية
that are still good.
هذه لا تزال جيدة
What do you want then?
ماذا إذن؟
Listen up. They are
استمع، هم
steamed quail,
السقي على البخار
fried duck webs, chicken tongue soup,
شبكات البط الصديقة، حساء لغة الدجاج
deer stomach with scallops,
معدة الغزلان مع حثالة
pan-fried beef tendons,
خيوط لحم البقر المقلي
rabbit shreds with chrysanthemum,
قشعريرة الأرانب مع الكريسانثيوم
deep-fried deer legs,
وساقيه الغزلان المقلي
and gold and silver hooves with ginger and vinegar.
وخراطيم الذهب والفضة مع الزنجبيل والخيضر
I just ordered what you can cook.
لقد طلبت فقط ما يمكنك الطهو به
As for expensive dishes,
أما بالنسبة للأطباء باهظة الثمن
I don't think you can make them.
لا أعتقد أنه يمكنك صنعها
These eight dishes
هذه الأطباق الثمانية
cost a lot.
باهظة الثمن
Just the duck webs and chicken tongue soup
فقط شبكات البط والحساء بلغة الدجاج
need dozens of ducks
بحاجة إلى عشرات البط
and chickens.
ودجاج
Well...
إذن
This gentleman will pay.
هذا الرجل النبيل سيدفع
Do you think he can't afford it?
هل تعتقد أنه لا يستطيع تحمل تكلفته؟
Well...
إذن
Is it enough?
هل يكفي؟
Yes. Yes.
أجل
I'll go prepare now.
سأذهب للاستعداد الآن
Do you need anything else?
هل تحتاج إلى أي شيء آخر؟
Eight dim sum dishes. That's enough.
ثمانية أطباق مسامية، هذا يكفي
What wine do you want?
ما نبيذ تريدين؟
What do you have?
ماذا لديك؟
We have ten-year-old
لدينا عشرة أعوام
Sanbai Fen wine.
نبيذ سمباي فين
How about two bottles?
ما رأيك بزجاجتين
That's not bad.
هذا ليس سيئًا
Okay.
حسنًا
Great.
عظيم
Please wait a moment.
انتظر لحظة من فضلك
You took too much.
بالغت في الأمر
No, I didn't.
لا، لم أفعل
Keep it.
احتفظي بها
You gave him too much.
لقد أعطيته الكثير
Actually, I have more.
في الحقيقة، لديّ المزيد
I've never
لم يسبق لي
seen such delicacies.
مثل هذه الأطباق
You've never been to Jiangnan?
لم تذهب أبدا إلى جيانغنان؟
An old saying goes,
يقول القول المأثور
"In Wu and Yue,
"في وو ويو
missing someone in dreams.
اختفى شخص ما في أحلام
Transparent tiles gleam over endless waves;
البلاط الشفاف يتأرجح على موجات لا نهاية لها ؛
A black awning boat carries the essence of spring.
يحمل قارب الصيد الأسود جوهر الربيع
In water towns, my soul finds repose."
في مدن المياه، نجد روحي رائحة "
This is Jiangnan.
أنا جيانغنان
Though I don't quite understand,
رغم أنني لا أفهم جيدًا
it sounds beautiful.
تبدو جميلةً
- Waiter! - Coming!
- رائع! - تعال!
Come here.
تعالوا إلى هنا
Yes, sir?
ماذا سيدي؟
Your scallops are five years old.
عمره خمس سنوات
How can you serve this?
كيف يمكنك خدمة هذا؟
I don't know that...
لا أعرف أنني...
Sir, I'm the manager.
سيدي، أنا المدير
You got it right,
لقد فهمت ذلك جيدا
indeed.
بالفعل
I apologize.
أنا أعتذر
Actually, we don't serve scallops.
في الواقع، نحن لا نخدم حثالة
These were just bought
شُريت هذه للتو
from the biggest restaurant here.
من أكبر المطاعم هنا
Then take them away.
إذن خذوهم بعيدًا
- Quickly, take them away. - Take them away.
- بسرعة، خذهم بعيدا - ابعدهم بسرعة - خذها بعيدًا
Let's go on.
دعنا نذهب
Here.
تفضلي
I'll use this one.
سأستخدم هذه
Okay.
حسنًا
Little brother, cheers.
أخي الصغير، نخبكم
Delicious.
لذيذ
Here.
تفضل
(Changqing Restaurant)
(مطعم تشانغتشينغ)
Have some of this.
لديه بعض من هذا
Big brother,
أخي الكبير
what are you looking at?
إلام تنظر؟
Little brother,
أخي الصغير
your skin is fair.
بشرتك فاتحة
Why make yourself dirty?
لماذا تجعل نفسك قذرة؟
We've been talking for too long.
نحن نتحدث منذ فترة طويلة
The food is cold.
الطعام بارد
It doesn't matter.
لا يهم
We can still eat them.
ما زال بإمكاننا تناولها
Not tasty anymore.
لم يعد لذيذًا
- Waiter! - Yes?
- نعم! - نعم
Remove these
ازيل هذه
cold dishes
الأطباق الباردة
and make a new set of dishes.
وأضع مجموعة جديدة من الأطباق
Clear the table!
نظف الطاولة!
Come, help clear the table.
تعالوا، ساعدوا في توضيح الطاولة
(Changqing Restaurant)
(مطعم تشانغتشينغ)
Big brother,
أخي كبير
thank you. Goodbye.
شكرًا لك، وداعًا
Hold on.
انتظر
Little brother,
أخي الصغير
we really hit it off.
نضربها حقًا
You're underdressed.
أنت يرتدون ملابس كافية
You can keep
يمكنك الاحتفاظ
my mink coat.
معطف منك
Also,
وأيضًا
here's some money.
هنا بعض المال
Here you are.
ها أنت ذا
Take it.
خذ هذا
Don't take others' buns.
لا تأخذ كعك الآخرين
Bye.
إلى اللقاء
Let's go.
لنذهب
Big brother.
أخ كبير
Little brother, what's wrong?
أخي الصغير، ما الخطب؟
May I know your name?
هل يمكنني أن أعرف اسمك؟
Oh, I forgot that.
لقد نسيت ذلك
My name is Guo Jing.
اسمي غو جينغ
And you?
وأنت؟
My family name is Huang,
اسمي هوانغ
given name Rong.
الاسم رونغ
Brother Huang.
الأخ هوانغ
Are you going back south?
هل ستعود إلى الجنوب؟
If so,
إذا كان الأمر كذلك
let's travel together.
دعنا نسافر معا
I'm not going back.
لا أعود
Why not go home?
لم لا أذهب إلى المنزل؟
My father threw me out.
رمني والدي في الخارج
How could that be?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك؟
He imprisoned a man,
لقد سجن رجلا
and wouldn't release him.
ولن أطلق سراحه
I felt sorry for him
شعرت بالأسف عليه
and worried he might be bored,
وأخشى أن يكون يشعر بالملل
so I brought him food and wine
لذلك أحضرت له الطعام والنبيذ
and talked to him.
وتحدثت إليه
My father found out
اكتشف والدي
and scolded me,
ووبخني
so I ran away at night.
لذلك هربت في الليل
How long have you been away?
منذ متى كنت بعيدا؟
Over a month.
أكثر من شهر
By now, your father
الآن، والدك
must be missing you.
لا بد أن يكون مفقودا لك
What about your mother?
ماذا عن أمك؟
She died long ago.
ماتت منذ فترة طويلة
I grew up without my mother.
نشأت من دون أمي
I'm the opposite.
أنا عكس ذلك
My father died early.
مات والدي مبكرا
My mother raised me.
رعتني أمي
Who is better,
من هو الأفضل
father or mother?
أبي أم؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف
Anyway, just go home
على أي حال، اذهبي إلى المنزل فحسب
after you've had fun.
بعد أن استمتعت
He threw me out. I won't go back.
رمى بي، لن أعود
No.
لا
Why doesn't he come for me?
لماذا لا يأتي من أجلي؟
Maybe he tried
ربما حاول
but couldn't find you.
لكنه لم يستطع إيجادك
That's true.
هذا صحيح
I'll go back when I'm done playing.
سأعود عندما أنتهي من العزف
Big brother,
أخي الأكبر
if I ask for a treasure,
إذا طلبت كنزا
can you give it to me?
هل يمكنك أعطيه لي؟
Of course. I'll give you
بالطبع، سأعطيك
anything you want.
أي شيء تريدين
I like your fine horse.
يعجبني حصان جيد لك
You like it? It's yours.
أنت تحبه؟ إنه لك
Here.
تفضلي
Really?
حقًا؟
I never lie.
أنا لا أكذب أبدا
Brother Huang, what's wrong?
الأخ هوانغ، ما هو الخطأ؟
Are you not feeling well?
ألست على ما يرام؟
Here. Get ready.
هنا، استعدي
Hold on.
انتظر
Red horse.
الحصان الأحمر
Today, I'm giving you away
اليوم، أنا أعطيك إياه
to my good friend, Brother Huang.
إلى صديقي العزيز، الأخ هوانغ
You must behave.
يجب أن تتصرف
Don't be a baby, okay?
لا تكن طفلةً، اتفقنا؟
Good.
جيد
Bye.
إلى اللقاء
(Martial Duel for a Spouse)
(الزميل الصغير للأب)
What's new over there?
ما الجديد هناك؟
What's so lively?
ما هو حيوي جدا؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
that's a martial duel for a spouse.
هذه زميلة عسكرية للزوج
Martial duel for a spouse?
زميلتي الأكبر للزوج؟
What's that?
ما هذا؟
A poor artist holds it
فنان مسكين يحملها
to marry off his daughter.
للزواج من ابنته
Whoever wins the duel
كل من يفوز بالدويل
can marry her.
يمكن أن تتزوجها
Interesting.
مثير للاهتمام
Let's go take a look.
لنذهب ونلق نظرة
Great! Great!
رائع!
Amazing!
مذهل!
(Mu Nianci) Great! Great!
"مو نيانسي" رائع!
Can't do it. I'll get beaten up there.
لا يمكن فعل ذلك، سأضرب هناك
Give it a try.
جربها
I'm Mu Yi
أنا مو يي
from Shandong.
من تشاندونغ
We pass here,
نمر هنا
not seeking fame or fortune.
ولا نسعى إلى الشهرة أو الحظ
It's just that my daughter is not married.
كل ما في الأمر أن ابنتي ليست متزوجة
She once made a wish
لقد حققت أمنية ذات مرة
not for a wealthy husband,
ليس لزوج ثري
but for a martial arts master.
ولكن من أجل معلم فنون الدفاع عن النفس
Make it specific!
اجعلي الأمر محددا!
- Tell us! - Yes.
- أخبرنا! - نعم
If anyone
إذا كان أي شخص
under 30 years old,
دون 30 سنة
unmarried,
غير متزوجة
can defeat my daughter in a fight,
يمكن أن يهزم ابنتي في قتال
he can have my promise to marry her.
يمكنه الحصول على وعدي للزواج منها
Make way!
ابتعد!
Don't look!
لا تنظروا!
Be quick!
كن سريعا!
Move!
هيا!
Move aside!
تنحوا جانبًا!
(Wanyan Kang, Prince of the Jin Empire)
(وانيان كانغ، أمير إمبراطورية جين)
Is this duel
هل هذا دويل
for this young lady?
لهذه الفتاة؟
I'm Mu.
أنا مو
How can I help you, Young Master?
كيف يمكنني مساعدتك يا سيد؟
I'd like to give it a try.
أود أن أجرب
Young Master is joking.
السيد يمزح
We are just rough folks.
نحن مجرد أوهام خشنة
How dare we spar with a Young Master?
كيف نجرؤ على الدوران مع سيد؟
Isn't anyone allowed
أليس هناك أحد مسموحا له
to come up and compete?
للظهور والمنافسة؟
I like duels.
أحب الدويل
Miss,
الآنسة
fight with me.
تشاجرا معي
Young Master,
السيد
this is not an ordinary duels and contests.
هذا ليس ندولا ومسابقات عادية
It concerns my daughter's marriage.
يتعلق الأمر بزواج ابنتي
Please understand.
يرجى فهم
How long have you been
منذ متى وأنت
holding the duel?
أمسك الدويل؟
Through seven rounds,
من خلال سبع جولات
it's been almost half a year.
مضى نحو نصف عام
And no one
ولا أحد
has defeated her?
هزمها؟
I don't believe that.
أنا لا أؤمن بذلك
I believe
أعتقد
either those with exceptional martial art skills are married,
إما أن أولئك الذين لديهم مهارات استثنائية فنون الدفاع عن النفس متزوجون
or they disdain fighting with my daughter.
أو ازدراء القتال مع ابنتي
Alright then,
حسنًا إذن
since we're both martial artists,
بما أننا فنانون قتاليون
I'll give it a try.
سأجرّب
Young Master,
سيد
why force the issue?
لماذا تجبر المشكلة؟
Let's spar respectfully, and that's it.
دعنا نتجادل بكل احترام، وهذا كل شيء
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I will not injure
لن أُصب
or hurt your daughter.
أو اجرح ابنتك
Miss, you just need to land one punch
آنسة، عليك فقط أن تلقي لكمة واحدة
on me to win.
لكي أفوز
Is that okay?
هل هذا على ما يرام؟
Martial duels
الزميلة الأكبر
demand fairness.
تتطلب الإنصاف
- Hurry up and start! - Yeah!
- أسرع وأبدأ! - نعم!
You two fight, get married
أنتما تشاجران، وتتزوجان
and have babies soon!
وتنجب أطفالا قريبا!
Miss,
الآنسة
shall we?
هلا نفعل؟
Fight, fight, fight!
لنقاتل!
Fight!
هيا!
Father.
أبي
Good.
جيد
Good!
جيد!
Good moves.
خطوات جيدة
She...
إنها...
Good! Amazing!
رائعة!
Clearly, you can defeat me,
من الواضح، يمكنك هزيمتي
but you kept holding back.
لكنك ظللت تكبح نفسي
Are you looking down on me?
هل تقلل من شأني؟
I'm not done yet. Keep going!
لم أنته بعد، تابعي!
If you want to have fun with me,
إن كنت تريدين أن تستمتعا بي
please go away.
أرجوك ابتعد
Both of us enjoy the duel.
كلانا يستمتع بالدويل
How could it just be me having fun?
كيف يمكن أن أكون أنا فقط أستمتع؟
Take my move.
خذ خطوتي
Don't step on me!
لا تتحركي!
Marry him.
تزوجه
Great! Great!
رائع!
Marry him! Marry him!
تزوجه!
Give it to me!
أعطيه إلي
Look at him.
انظر إليه
Young Master,
سيد
may I ask your name?
هل يمكنني أن أسألك عن اسمك؟
I don't think it's necessary.
لا أعتقد أنه ضروري
We live at Gaosheng Inn
نحن نعيش في نزل غاوشنغ
on the West street.
في الشارع الغربي
Let's go and have a talk there.
دعونا نذهب ونتحدث هناك
Talk about what?
عمّ تتحدث؟
You and your daughter
أنت وابنتك
don't take the duel seriously.
لا تأخذ الدويل على محمل الجد
Never mind,
لا عليك
I'm going home.
أنا سأذهب إلى المنزل
Since you defeated my daughter,
بما أنك هزمت ابنتي
I'll marry her
سأتزوجها
to you.
لك
It's about the marriage.
إنه يتعلق بالزواج
We can't be careless.
لا يمكن أن نكون مهملين
We can have a fight.
يمكننا أن نخوض معركة
It's fun.
إنه ممتع
But marry her?
لكن تزوجها؟
I don't think so.
لا أعتقد ذلك
And miss didn't dodge
ولم تتفاد الآنسة ذلك
or block my palm strike.
أو تمنع إضرابي عن النخيل
It's unfair for me to win.
من غير العادل بالنسبة لي أن أفوز
Young Master,
سيدي
are you making jokes on us?
هل تمزح معنا؟
My daughter
ابنتي
cannot marry such a frivolous person.
لا يمكن أن تتزوج مثل هذا الشخص العاجز
Give the shoe back!
تراجع الحذاء!
She gave it to me.
أعطتني إياها
What's it to you?
ما الأمر لك؟
Although I'm not marrying her,
على الرغم من أنني لا أتزوجها
I can't refuse the award.
لا يمكنني رفض القرار
One can be killed but not humiliated.
يمكن قتل أحدهم ولكن لا يهان
Father!
أبي!
♪I wander in the martial world♪
♪ أتجول في عالم القتال ♪
♪I drink a thousand cups of wine and sing to the sky♪
♪ أشرب ألف كوب من النبيذ والغناء إلى السماء ♪
♪Life and death intertwined♪
♪ الحياة والموت متشابكين ♪
♪Leaning against the railing and shouting♪
♪ الوقوف ضد الغرق والنار ♪
♪Stars and moon over the wild expanse♪
♪ النجوم والقمر فوق التوسع البري ♪
♪Longbows shooting toward the distant sun♪
♪ أصوات طويلة تطلق نحو الشمس البعيدة ♪
♪We meet in mountains and rivers♪
♪ نلتقي في الجبال والأنهار ♪
♪Rushing through narrow paths♪
♪ التحرك عبر مسارات ضيقة ♪
♪I wander through the martial world♪
♪ تتجول في عالم القتال ♪
♪All glitz mere illusions♪
♪ كل ألفاظ بسيطة ♪
♪Cutting off all debts♪
♪ إلغاء جميع الديون ♪
♪Only the shadows of swords and gleaming blades can be seen♪
♪ فقط ظلال السيوف والشفرات الكاذبة يمكن رؤيتها ♪
♪Fearless, undaunted♪
♪ لا خوف ولا مهرب ♪
♪The marial world is a lifetime of daring♪
♪ العالم الملكي هو حياة من الجرأة ♪
♪Who knows my dreams and ambitions♪
♪ من يعرف أحلامي وطموحاتي ♪
♪Wakening to find them as distant dreams♪
♪ الاستيقاظ للعثور عليهم كأحلام بعيدة ♪
♪The road ahead is long♪
♪ الطريق إلى الأمام طويل ♪
♪The path is vast and grand♪
♪ الطريق شاسع ودقيق ♪
♪Thousands of dreams span ages♪
♪ بآلاف الأحلام تمتد عبر الأعمار ♪
♪Whirling and swirling♪
♪ الحيلة والسباحة ♪
♪Ask the youth what it means♪
♪ اطلب من الشباب ما يعنيه ♪
♪Heroes face all challenges♪
♪ الأبطال يواجهون جميع التحديات ♪
♪True to their hearts♪
♪ أرغب في قلوبهم ♪
♪Or lost in the dust♪
♪ أو خسر في الغبار ♪
♪The road ahead is long♪
♪ الطريق إلى الأمام طويل ♪
♪The path is vast and grand♪
♪ الطريق شاسع وغالي ♪
♪People in the world varied and numerous♪
♪ الناس في العالم متنوعون وعديدون ♪
♪Whirling and swirling♪
♪ الحيلة والسباحة ♪
♪Who truly understands♪
♪ من يفهم ♪ حقا
♪Heroes face all challenges♪
♪ الأبطال يواجهون جميع التحديات ♪
♪Searching to truly grasp♪
♪ ابحث عن فهم ♪ حقا
♪Only then do they discern♪
♪ إذن لا يتلاحظوا ♪
♪Achievements and mistakes are transient♪
♪ الإنجازات والأخطاء عابرة ♪
♪To the end, yet steps persist♪
♪ حتى النهاية، لكن الخطوات لا تزال مستمرة ♪
♪We can feel pain and also joy♪
♪ يمكننا أن نشعر بالألم والسعادة ♪
♪We can charge forward or retreat♪
♪ يمكننا أن نتراجع للأمام ♪
♪No need to look back♪
♪ لا داعي للنظر إلى الوراء ♪
♪Rush through wind and clouds, shake the universe♪
♪ مرور الرياح والسحب، تهز الكون ♪
♪No matter the journey's length♪
♪ لا يهم طول الرحلة ♪
♪Entering the martial world♪
♪ دخول عالم القتال ♪
♪I fear not the endless journey♪
♪ لا أخشى الرحلة التي لا نهاية لها ♪